Guide to the Bruce Cratsley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bruce Cratsley papers
1975-1998
1980-1995
MS 1836
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
24.75
(18 boxes)
The papers consist of photographic prints by and topical files of Bruce Cratsley. Also included is White Light, Silent Shadows, a book of Cratsley's photography.
Cratsley, Bruce, 1944-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Bruce Cratsley Archive and William Leight, 2004, Jane Cratsley, 2006, and John Cratsley, 2008.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged by size and chronologically therein.
Biographical / Historical
Bruce Cratsley was born in Canton, Pennsylvania, and graduated from Swarthmore College. His interest in photography led him to study under Lisette Model at the New School for Social Research in the early 1970s. His work was displayed in prominent New York galleries and ranged from portraits of friends, to still lifes and photographs of gay and lesbian culture in New York City. A retrospective of his work was mounted at the Brooklyn Museum of Art in 1996 to critical acclaim. White Light, Silent Shadows, containing a selection of his photographs, was published in 1998. Bruce Cratsley died on June 29, 1998, of complications from AIDS.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist photographic prints by and topical files of Bruce Cratsley. Also included is White Light, Silent Shadows, a book of Cratsley's photography.
Gays -- New York (State); Homosexuality in art; Lesbians -- New York (State); Photography, Artistic; Black-and-white photographs; Photographers; LGBTQ resource; Cratsley, Bruce, 1944-
- Inventory, 1975-1998
  Scope and Contents
  All titles and dates are from a list provided by the donors. The photographs are arranged by size. Within size, they are arranged chronologically, and within year, alphabetically by title. Where titles and dates found on the backs of photographs vary from those on the donor list, the variants are listed in quotation marks in square brackets. For photographs published in White Light, Silent Shadows (Santa Fe: Arena Editions, 1998), published title and page number are indicated in square brackets.
  - White Light, Silent Shadows, 1998 (Box 1)
  - 15x15 prints
    - Richard Shaving ["1979"; published as "Richard Shaving, 1980," p. 153; smaller version of this photograph in box 3: "Richard Shaving"], 1977 (Box 2)
    - Grace Church ["Grace Church, Broadway and East 10th, NYC, 1988"; smaller version of this photograph is in box 4: "Grace Church"], 1983 (Box 2)
    - Forbidden Planet [smaller version in box 4: "Forbidden Planet 1984"] (Box 2)
    - Lifting Hand ["Lifting Hand (Scott Cohen) Chez Moi"], 1986 (Box 2)
    - Mask and Mirrored Self ["1986"], 1987 (Box 2)
    - Sister Missionary Delight, Gay Parade, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Susan Orton ["Suzanne Orton, Chez Moi"], 1987 (Box 2)
    - Wings of Light ["Wings of Light (John M.)"], 1987 (Box 2)
    - Coming or Going [smaller version in box 4: "Two Figures and Sphere 1987"], 1988 (Box 2)
    - Peter van de Kamp, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Piano Hands ["Piano Hands (Crosby), Chelsea Hotel"], 1988 (Box 2)
    - R., 1988 ["Rukavina"; published as "Gregory Rukavina, At His Studio, 1988," p. 94] (Box 2)
    - Madison Avenue Angel ["1988"], 1989 (Box 2)
    - Tree, Branches and Grate ["Tree, Branches and Grate, Metropolitan Museum"], 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bruce Still Life [" 'Bruce', Still Life"], 1990 (Box 2)
    - Piano Hand, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Powdered David [published as "Powdered David, At Home, 1990," p.76] (Box 2)
    - Skeleton Hand at Piano ["Skeleton Hand at Piano (Close Up), Julie Taymore Studio"], 1990 (Box 2)
    - Big Hat and Glitter, Gay Parade, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Death Float, Gay Parade, NYC ["Death Float, Gay Parade"], 1991 (Box 2)
    - Float of Drag Queens, Gay Parade, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Leg ["Ron's White Leg (Cardinal Cooke Hospital), NYC"; published as "White Leg (Ron in the Hospice), 1991," p. 155] (Box 2)
    - Big White Begonia, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Plant Feet and TV ["Plant, Feet and T.V., at Home"], 1993 (Box 2)
    - Medieval Tomb of Woman, Louvre, Paris ["Medieval Tomb of Woman, Richelieu Wing, Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 2)
    - Pall Bearer at Tomb of Palippepot ["Pallbearer at Tomb of Palippepot, Seneschel of Burgundy, French 15th C., Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 2)
    - Hospital Hand (Billy), undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled (Head), undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled (penis protruding from jeans), undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled (Top Hat) [same as "Composition with Leg and Pile of Photos" in box 4], undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled (Torn Jeans), undated (Box 2)
  - 10x10 prints
    - Trespasso, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Block of Ice, East 28th Street 3 AM, NYC, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Bottle in My Window, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Richard Shaving [larger version of this photograph in box 2: "Richard Shaving"], 1977 [c.1980] (Box 3)
    - Christ Figure, Venice ["Christ Figure, Venice, Oct 1980"] (Box 3)
    - Egyptian Staircase ["Egyptian Staircase (Louvre)," published under same title p. 34], 1980 (Box 3)
    - Four Kings and Two Tourists, Venice, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ponte della Pieta, Venice, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Il Redentore from across Giudecca Canal, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Rising Water Near Grand Canal [published as "Rising Water Near the Grand Canal, Venice," p. 39], 1980 (Box 3)
    - Tourist and Colossus ["Tourist and Colossus, Venice Library"], 1980 (Box 3)
    - Venetian Hearts, Venice, 1980 (Box 3)
    - View toward Moro, Venice, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Zattere al Gesuati ["Zattere al Gaesuati, Venice"], 1980 (Box 3)
    - Draft in Venice, Two Chairs, Lido ["Two Chairs, Lido (Death in Venice)"], 1982 (Box 3)
    - Hand of Tom Brazil [published as "The Hand of Tom Brazil, Chez Moi, 1987," p. 156], 1982 (Box 3)
    - Saint and Martyr, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Stairs from the Palazzo, Venice ["Stairs from Palazo, Venice"], 1982 (Box 3)
    - Torcello Basilica, Door with Cross ["Torcello Basilica, Door with Cross"], 1982 (Box 3)
    - Venice Alley at Night, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Wall Cherub, Venice ["Wall Cherub, Venice, July 1982"] (Box 3)
    - Grace Church ["Tree and Shadows, Grace Church, 1988"; larger version of this photograph in box 2: "Grace Church"], 1983 (Box 4)
    - Moore Sculpture, Storm King NY ["Henry Moore Sculpture, Storm King, Nov 1982"], 1983 (Box 4)
    - Elvis Teardrops ["Elvis Teardrops, NYC"; published as "Elvis Teardrops, 1984" inp. 159] (Box 4)
    - Gum Balls, Soho [published as "Gumballs, Soho, 1994," p. 58], 1984 (Box 4)
    - Soldier, Sailor, Marine, Gay Parade NYC ["3 Faces, Gay Parade, 1984"; published as "Soldier, Sailor, and Marine, Gay Parade, New York City," p. 70] (Box 4)
    - Banana Mannequin, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Bronzing (Helen Gazagnaire) ["Bronzing (Hellen Gazagnaire) West Cornwall, Conn."], 1985 (Box 4)
    - Forbidden Planet [larger version of this photograph in box 2: "Forbidden Planet 1984"], 1985 (Box 4)
    - Leopard, Skull and Eggs, 1986 (Box 4)
    - New Jersey Tulips ["1985," published as "Terry's Tulips, New Jersey, 1985," p. 131], 1986 (Box 4)
    - New Year's Day, Chez Moi, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Pitcher and Goblets, Chez Moi ["Photo, Pitcher and Goblets, Chez Moi"], 1986 (Box 4)
    - Television Head, Barney's 7th Avenue, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Balloon and Ribbon ["New Year's Day (Robert N.)"; published as "New Year's Balloon, Chez Moi," p. 11], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Chris, Very Close, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Chris's Leg, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Composition with Leg and Pile of Photos [same as "Top Hat" in box 2], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Encased and Bound Montage, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Headless Portrait ["Headless Portrait (S. Gianailos) At Home"], 1987 (Box 4)
    - John in Sin, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Keith A. Looking Up, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Keith Ardent from Above, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Madison Classical, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Man and Dog Still-Life [published as "Man and Dog Still Life, Table at Home," p. 144], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Ms. Mutfit, Chez Moi ["1986," published under same title, p. 78], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Reclining Nude ["Reclining Nude (Dennis D.) Chez Moi"], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Skull and Screen ["1988"], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Sunlit Figure [published as "Body of Light (John M.)," p. 151], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Three Photos, Annex Flea Market, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Two Figures and Sphere, Madison Ave., NY [larger version of photograph in box 2: "Coming or Going 1988"], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Window Curtain ["Window Curtain, Mohonk Mountain Lodge"], 1987 (Box 4)
    - Albert's Closet [published under same title in p. 57], 1988 (Box 4)
    - Bag Heads [published as "Bag Heads, West 57th Street, New York City, 1988," p. 112] (Box 4)
    - Candlestick, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Crotch and Leg in Sun (Chris), 1988 (Box 4)
    - Halloween David, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Torn, Sunn [sic] Struck Face, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Torn--Torso and Face, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Beach Love Fire Island, 1989 (Box 4)
    - David Halloween, 1989 (Box 4)
    - David Profile [published as "Portrait of David K. Waine (1958-1991), 1990," p. 77], 1989 (Box 4)
    - David, Soft-Profile, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Diego, Close-Up, 1989 (Box 4)
    - 19th Century Mudras ["19th Century Mudra"], 1989 (Box 4)
    - Rosenbach Christ ["Rosenbach Christ, Philadelphia," published under same title, p. 102], 1989 (Box 4)
    - Sad-Eyed David, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Serge Lifar Poster ["Serge Lifar Poster, E. Buk, Spring St, NYC"; published as "Serge Lifar Dance Poster and Machine, E. Buk, Spring Street, Soho, New York City, 1991], 1989 (Box 4)
    - Basket of Onions ["Basket of Onions, Dean of Delucca"], 1990 (Box 4)
    - Body Heat, East Village [published as "Body Heat, East Village, New York City" in p. 51], 1990 (Box 4)
    - Burst Balloon ["Burst Balloon, Midtown NYC"; "1991"; published as "Burst Balloon, Midtown, New York City, 1989," p. 44], 1990 (Box 4)
    - Face in the Street ["Face in the Street (Myles [sic] Davis, 1989"; published as "Face in the Street, East Village, New York City, 1990," p. 45] (Box 4)
    - Jack from Below, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Lightstruck David, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Neck and Ear (David), 1990 (Box 4)
    - Neck in Sunlight (David) ["Neck in Sunlight"], 1990 (Box 4)
    - Omo Soho ["Omo Soho (Bald and Naked)"], 1990 (Box 5)
    - Painting and Sculpture ["Painting and Sculpture, Shepherd Gallery, 1989," published as "Painting and Sculpture, Shepherd Gallery, New York City, 1990," p. 103] (Box 5)
    - Shadow/Body, 1990 (Box 5)
    - String Game-David (Body), 1990 (Box 5)
    - String Game-David (Head), 1990 (Box 5)
    - Whale-Man, Fire Island ["Whale-Man, Fire Island Pines"], 1990 (Box 5)
    - Whale-Man, Fire Island, 1990 (Box 5)
    - David and His Animal Friends ["David and Animal Friends (Resting from AIDS Treatments, in comfort)"; published as "David in Bed Hugging His 'Animal Friends' At Home," p. 75], 1991 (Box 5)
    - David Mug Shot ["David Mug Shot (K. S. Lesions)"], 1991 (Box 5)
    - David Nude in Bed [same as "Nude David" also in box 5], 1991 (Box 5)
    - Indian Head Ring ["Indian Head Ring 1991, 'He studied the Lesions on His Body Again and Again'"] (Box 5)
    - Last Photo of David, Crown and Anchor Hotel ["Last Photo of David, Crown and Anchor Hotel, Provincetown June 24, 1991"] (Box 5)
    - Nude David [same as "David Nude in Bed" also in box 5], 1991 (Box 5)
    - Photo of Photo of Photo, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Resting Close-Up, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Two Glass Spheres Reflected, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Walking Table, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Big Billy, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Billy at the Met, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Billy's Roses, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Butterfly Crotch, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Dress Reflection of Billy and Bruce, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Four Glass Balls Reflected, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Kiss Necktie, Broadway, NYC, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Leight Smile (Billy), 1992 (Box 5)
    - Poster War II ["Poster Window, 1991"], 1992 (Box 5)
    - Trinity of Water Lilies, Longwood Gardens ["Trinity, Longwood Gardens"; published as "Trinity of Waterlily Pads, Longwood Gardens," p. 125], 1992 (Box 5)
    - Barbie at X-Mas [published as "Christmas Barbie, At Home, 1995," p. 76], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Billy in Bed (Face), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Billy on Bed (Nude), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Billy in Cornfield, East Hampton, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Billy Reflected, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Billy Sleeping (Head and Hand), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Close-up From Rear (Billy), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Clownish (Billy), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Dorothy's Tulips [published as "Dorothy's Tulips Viewed Toward the Light," p. 130], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Eight Roses ["1992"], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Hair/Light, Billy Close-Up [published as "Billy Leight, Hair Lit," p. 82], 1993 (Box 5)
    - His Face (Billy), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Legs and Arms of Billy, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Legs and Bottom in Shadow (Billy) ["Legs and Bottom in Shadow"], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Legs of Billy on Daybed, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Neck of Rupert F., 1993 (Box 5)
    - Nude Billy in Bed ["Shiny Fin...(illegible hand-writing) (Billy)"; published as "Nude Billy in Bed," p. 83], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Potted Tree in Window of Vases ["Potted Tree in Window of Vases, Windy Willows"], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Sad Billy (Close-Up) [published as "Sad Billy, at Home, 1993," p. 80] (Box 5)
    - Shadowed Legs (Billy) ["Shadowed Legs"], 1993 (Box 5)
    - Shaving Billy, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Sunday Morning Coffee (Billy), 1993 (Box 5)
    - Big Fairy, Gay Parade ["Big Fairy, (illegible writing) Park, Gay Parade"], 1994 (Box 5)
    - Billy Buttocks and Foot, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Billy in Morning Sun (Guido Shirt), 1994 (Box 5)
    - Billy on Vacation ["Billy on Vacation (illegible writing) NY"], 1994 (Box 5)
    - Earth Angel, NYC, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Glove, Hand, Banana (Billy), 1994 (Box 5)
    - "Guido" Billy, Close-Up, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Little Wedding Dress, Beaded Top, Side Window [published as "Petite Dummy Wearing Beaded Bodice Wedding Gown, 1995," p. 59], 1994 (Box 5)
    - The Peeled Banana, Billy Chez Moi, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Proud and Gowned ["Proud and Gowned, Gay Parade"], 1994 (Box 5)
    - Renaissance Torso, Met Museum, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Wrapped Mannequin, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Admiration of Youth, Muse D'Orsay, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Balustrades in Shadow ["Balustrades in Shadow, Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Billy and His Amaryllis, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Billy in Bed (Bending Over), 1995 (Box 6)
    - Billy Uncombed, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Bowl of Pansies and Scattered Leaves ["Bowl of Pansies and Scattered Leaves, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris, Nov. 1995"] (Box 6)
    - Crucifixion of Broken Stained Glass ["Crucifixion of Broken Stained Glass, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Equestrian Bronze of Charlemagne ["Equestrian Statue of Charlemagne, 8th c.?, Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Flower Decked Grave Cemetery Montmartre ["Floral Bedecked Grave, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Fresh Tomatoes ["Fresh Tomatoes, Rue Poncelet Market, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Renoir Statue Bust in Case, Musée D'Orsay, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Funeral Monument of D. Guy Pitchal ["Funeral Monument of D. Guy Pitchal, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Guimard Decorations ["Guimard Decorations, Parc Monceau Metropolitain, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Immobile Mime ["Paris, Dusil, Outside D'Orsay, Immobile Mime"; published as "Immobile Mime, Evening in Paris," p. 52], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Martyrdom in Stained Glass ["Martyrdom in Stained Glass, Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Memorial Tombstone, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Monument and Tree Branches ["Monument and Tree Branches, Parc Monceau, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Monument, Parc Monceau, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Mushrooms for Sale ["Mushrooms for Sale, Rue Poncelet Market, 17th Arrond. Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - 19th C Painting of Two Pheasants ["19th c Painting of Two Pheasants, Outside Antique Shop, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Older Man in Conversation ["Older Man in Conversation, Cafe in Palais Royale, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Pall Bearers Carrying Sarcophagus ["Pallbearers Carrying Sarcophagus of Palippepot Seneschel of Burgundy, French 13th c., Louvre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Parc Monceau Paris, Antiquated Sculpture, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Passage into Richelieu Pavilion [published as "Passage into Richlieu Wing, Louvre, Paris," p. 30], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Pierced Door to Family Tomb ["Pierced Door to Family Tomb, Portraits Visible Inside, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Pigeon Man, Palais Royale, Paris, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Portable Arc de Triumph [published as "Arc de Triomphe Painted on Window, Paris," p. 55], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Portrait of M. Walther, Picasso Museum ["Portrait of M. Walther, Picasso Museum, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Profile of Billy, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Bronze Apple, Musée D'Orsay Museum, Paris ["Bronze Apple in Hand, D'Orsay Museum, Paris, 1995"] (Box 6)
    - Sandwiches Shop, Paris in the Marais, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Shadow Man, W. M. Hunt's Bath, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Skull on Table ["'Magical' Room, Louvre, Skull on Table on Wall, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Smiling Male Mannequin Head Wearing Scarf, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Smiling Man (Mannequin), Close-Up with Scarf ["Smiling Man (Mannequin), Close-Up with Scarf, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Statue Monument with Homage ["Statue Monument in Homage, Parc Monceau, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Tomb Monument of Dalida ["Tomb Monument of Dalida, Cemetery Montmartre, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Tree in Silhouette by Fence of Parc Monceau, 1995 (Box 6)
    - View Between Tombs, Montmartre Cemetery, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Woman (and Man) in Cafe ["Woman (and Man) in Cafe, Arcade of Palais Royale, Interior Courtyard, Paris"], 1995 (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Billy with Glasses), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (David's Face-Half in Shadow), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (David with Crystals on Eyes), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (David with Hands on Chest), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Joint), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Man Applying Shaving Cream), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Man in Hat Looking to Side), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Man on Bed with Leg in Air), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Man on Chair Looking Down), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Nude David with Rings), undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Torn), undated (Box 6)
- Additional Material, circa 1970s-1996; Accession 2007-M-042
  This accession consists of black and white photographic prints and topical files. The topical files contain correspondence, announcements, reviews and other publicity, and a resume documenting Cratsley's professional life, particularly his shows and other projects.
  Arrangement
  All titles and dates are from a list provided by the donors. The accession is arranged in two sections: photographs and topical files. The photographs are arranged by size. Within size, they are arranged chronologically, and within year, alphabetically by title. Where titles and dates found on the backs of photographs vary from those on the donor list, the variants are listed in quotation marks in square brackets. For photographs published in White Light, Silent Shadows (Santa Fe: Arena Editions 1998), published title and page number are indicated in square brackets. The topical files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Photographs
    - 15 X 15 prints
      - Untitled ["Forklift in Bright Morning Sun Chelsea, New York City, 1986"] (Box 1)
      - Roman Face, 1990, III, XXXV ["Roman Portrait Sculpture of Young Man with Bearded Face, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City, 1987"] (Box 1)
      - Bus Shelter Graffiti ["Bus Shelter Graffiti, Avenue A, New York City, 1987"], 1989 (Box 1)
      - Untitled ["Window with Gallery Reflection and View Toward a Rainy Autumnal Central Park, 1993"] (Box 1)
      - Untitled ["Budding Amaryllis at Home, 1994"] (Box 1)
      - Untitled ["Egyptian Portrait Fragment in Stone, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City, 1995"] (Box 1)
    - 10x10 ( and smaller) prints
      - Self with Nikormat, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Self, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Baby Sam, 17th Street Gallery, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - For Lisette, Met Museum ["For Lisette, 1987"], 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Lacock Abbey ["Lacock Abbey, Wiltshire, England, 1980"] (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Parade, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Street Kiss, Venice, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Tree Shrouded Alley, Venice, 1980 October (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - British Museum (Kick) ["Elgin Marbles (Kick), British Museum, London, 1982"] (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Guidecca Festival, Fireworks, Venice, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Kouros, Glyptothek, Munich, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Boy in Baseball Cap, Christopher Street, NYC, 1983 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Brooklyn Bridge, II, Centennial ["Centennial Fireworks, Brooklyn Bridge, New York City, 1983"] (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Isaac Masked ["Isaac Masked, Chez Moi, 1985"], 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Mc Dermott and McGough, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Bone China, Tribeca, NYC ["Bone China, Tribeca Graffiti and Paper Collage, New York City, 1984"] (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - D.C. Different Drummer, Gay Parade, NYC, 1984 June (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - J.B. Cat, East Houston Street, New York, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - One Way, Third Avenue, NYC, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Bad Boy, Greenwich Village, NYC ["Bad Boy, Seventh Avenue South, New York, 1985"] (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Botero Venus ["Botero Reclining Woman, Marlborough Gallery, New York, 1985"] (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Men of All Colors, Gay Parade, 5th Ave., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - N.Y., T-Shirt, Gay Parade, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Peter Hujar, Cooper Square, 1985 February (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Richard Smoking ["Richard Smoking, Chez Moi, 1985"] (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Sycamore Park, East 29th Street, NYC ["Sycamore Park, East 29th Street, New York City, 1986"], 1985 February (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Window, Bloomingdale's ["Mannequin and Idol, Bloomingdale's New York, 1985"] (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Bandana Man, Gay Parade, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Bare Back, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Black and White Jams, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 June (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Blond Black Dancing, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Circles and Moons, Soho ["Circles and Moons, Soho, New York City, 1986"] (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Fred and His Mother, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hammer and Hand, East 57th, NYC ["Hand and Hammer, East 57th Street, New York, 1985"], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Headless Self, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Looking at Photos, Chez Moi, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Man in Calder T-shirt, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Man with Tambourine in Sun, Gay Parade, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Mask and Reflected Self ["Mask and Reflected Self, Glass Shop, Lexington Avenue, New York, 1987"], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Orchids Blossoming at Don's ["Orchids Growing at Don's, New York City, 1986"] (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Reagan's a Dope, Pro-Pot Float (Queen's Queens For Cannabis), Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Scott and Bob, 1986 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Self In Quarter-Moon Mirror, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Self In Round Mirror, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Spectator (Pirate) 5th Avenue, NYC, Gay Parade, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Spectator in T-shirt and Blue Jeans, Gay Parade, NYC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - The Velvet Hat, University PL., NYC ["The Velvet Hat, New York, 1986"] (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Untitled ["Large Shadow, Sixth Avenue, New York City, 1986"] (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Untitled ["Mask and Tubes, Adam Kurtzman Studio, New York, 1986"] (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - All-Star, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)